flightline.co.uk 2008-11-01

# Privacy Policy - Flightline.co.uk

#### General Policy Details

Any personal information you provide to us including and similar to your name, address, telephone number and e-mail address will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside of Flightline Essex Ltd. Except where required by us to process your booking and to ensure that your travel arrangements run smoothly and meet your requirements we need to use the information you provide such as name, address, any special needs/dietary requirements etc.

We take full responsibility for ensuring that proper security measures are in place to protect your information. We must pass the information on to the relevant suppliers of your travel arrangements such as your tour operator, airlines, hotels, transport companies etc. The information may also be provided to security or credit checking companies, public authorities such as customs/immigration if required by them, or as required by law.

Additionally, where your holiday is outside the European Economic Area (EEA), controls on data protection in your destination may not be as strong as the legal requirements in this country. We will not however, pass any information onto any person not responsible for part of your travel arrangements. This applies to any sensitive information that you give to us such as details of any disabilities, or dietary/religious requirements. **(If we cannot pass this information to the relevant suppliers, whether in the EEA or not, we cannot provide your booking. In making this booking, you consent to this information being passed on to the relevant persons.)**

Usually your tour operator or other principal will pass this information onto their suppliers once we have provided it to them. The tour operator or other principal's use of your information is subject to their policy, both in respect of your booking and any future marketing, and is their responsibility. Please ask either us or them for a copy of this if you would like to see it.

Your data controller is: **Flightline Essex Limited.**

Please note consumers have a right of access to data held.

We will hold your information, where collected by us, and may use it to inform you of offers in the future. If you do not wish to receive such approaches in the future, please contact us at Client Data Protection, Flightline Essex Limited, Flightline House, 32-38 Milton Road, Westcliff-on-Sea, Essex SS0 7JE.

#### Credit/Debit Card Details

We know of no documented cases of credit card fraud using our website to purchase flights and holidays over the Internet. All credit card numbers are encrypted in the software when the booking is made using 128-bit encryption. They are only decrypted after they reach our computer. They are not held in clear text on any website.

#### Links to External Sites

Flightline Essex Ltd is not responsible for the content of external internet sites. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information. 

Unless otherwise stated ABTA protection does not apply to any of the third parties websites that we link to.

#### Cookies - What are they?

They are small data text files attached to your computer's hard-drive by your internet browser. They enable us to recognize you each time you visit this site and monitor the pages on our website that a computer used by you has accessed. 

#### Cookies - How do we use them?

We use cookies only for tracking purposes. The cookies that we use store the address (URL) of the website you visited before visiting this website. This information is for internal use only to help us in the marketing of this website. We do not publish or pass this information onto any third parties. 

Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information, and Flightline Essex Ltd does not use cookies to collect personal information. If you wish, you can change your internet browser settings to refuse cookies. 

#### Remember The Risks Whenever You Use The Internet!

While we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to Flightline Essex Ltd and you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. In addition other Internet sites or services that may be accessible through Flightline Essex Ltd have separate data and privacy practices independent of us, and therefore we disclaim any responsibility or liability for their policies or actions.

Please contact those vendors and others directly if you have any questions about their privacy policies.

For any other information email [webmaster](mailto:webmaster@flightline.co.uk "Contact the webmaster via email")

Flightline Privacy Policy Updated: **17th March 2007**
